backpage.com 2016-12-30

# backpage.com

**Privacy Policy  
Last Revised: _September 26, 2016_**

backpage.com and its affiliates (collectively, the “Site”) respect your privacy. Here is our Privacy Policy for this Site:

**Acceptance of Privacy Policy**

Each time you access, use, post, submit a post or reply, or browse the Site, you signify your acceptance of the then-current Privacy Policy.  If you do not accept this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to use the Site and must discontinue use of the Site immediately.

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We collect personal information about you whenever you engage in commerce transactions on the Site, use the Site’s products or services, request information or materials, create or update account information, place orders or make purchases, communicate with us, or visit the Site. The personal information we collect and store about you may include without limitation your first and last name, email address, credit or debit card number, telephone numbers, billing and shipping information, order history, and other non-public information about you.

We may use the information we collect to: 

  * Provide superior services; 
  * Keep you apprised of information and developments that you may find of interest; 
  * Alert you to new features, terms, content, products or services; 
  * Contact you regarding your posts, replies, and/or account information; 
  * Process and respond to your inquires; 
  * Improve the Site; 
  * Administer, monitor and control use of the Site, including posts, replies, and account information; and 
  * Enforce the Terms of Use (collectively, the “Activities”).

You authorize the Site to transmit email to you to respond to your communications and administer Activities. If you choose to receive mobile notifications, you authorize and agree that the Site may send text messages to your mobile phone, and you will be responsible for any message or data charges that may apply..

 **Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties**

We may disclose your personal information to agents and operators under confidentiality or similar agreements, including shippers, vendors, payment processors, and advertisers, who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information: (i) to provide products or services to you; (ii) to administer our business or the Site, including fulfilling and shipping orders; (iii) to provide customer service; (iv) to update account information; (v) to forward updates, announcements, and newsletters; (vi) to respond to your communications, and communicate with you about the Site and other activities related to the Site; (vii) in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or disposition of all or any portion of the Site’s business or operations (including without limitation in connection with bankruptcy or any similar proceedings); or (viii) as otherwise authorized by you. 

We integrate third party software which collects information about users for security purposes. Information collected by reCAPTCHA is held in accordance with the Google Privacy Policy.

**Disclosure in Other Circumstances**

We may also disclose your name, email address, telephone numbers, or other information about you, including personal information if (i) required to do so by law, court order or subpoena, or as requested by other government, law enforcement, or investigative authority, (ii) we in good faith believe that such disclosure is necessary or advisable, including without limitation to protect the rights or properties of the Site, (iii) we have reason to believe that disclosing your personal information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, or has breached an agreement, or if anyone else could be harmed by such activities or interference, (iv) if we determine an ad posted violates our Terms of Use or the rights of a third party, or (v) there is an emergency involving personal danger.  We may also provide information about you if we believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required or permitted by law. 

Please note that if you post any of your personal information on the Site, such information may be collected and used by others over whom the Site has no control. The Site is not responsible for the use by third parties of information you post or otherwise make public.

**Collection of Non-Personal Information Using Cookies**

We and certain service providers operating on our behalf collect information about your activity on our Site using tracking technologies such as cookies. This tracking data is used for many purposes, including, for example, to (i) deliver relevant content based on your preferences, usage patterns and location; (ii) monitor and evaluate the use and operation of our Site; and (iii) analyze traffic on our Site and on the sites of third parties. 

Non-personal information collected includes, without limitation, your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, the pages you request, the type of computer operating system you use (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS), the type of browser you use (e.g., Firefox, Chrome or Internet Explorer), the domain name of the Internet service provider, your activities while visiting the Site and the content you accessed. We may also collect your geolocation information when you visit our Site, including location information either provided by a mobile device interacting with our Site, or associated with your IP address, where we are permitted by law to process this information. 

Advertisers and third parties also may collect information about your activity on our Site and on third-party sites and applications using tracking technologies. Tracking data collected by these advertisers and third parties is used to decide which ads you see on third-party sites and applications, but does not identify you personally. You may choose not to receive targeted advertising from many ad networks, data exchanges, marketing analytics and other service providers. You may also choose to control targeted advertising you receive within applications by using your mobile device settings (for example, by re-setting your device’s advertising identifier and/or opting out of interest based ads). We adhere to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.

**Communication from the Site/Opt-Out**

From time to time, we may send you information with announcements and updates about the Site and your account. You may elect to opt-out of ongoing e-mail communication from us, such as newsletters, subscriptions, account information, promotional materials, contest results, survey inquiries, etc. by using a simple “opt out” procedure. You need only reply to the communication with the word “unsubscribe” (without the quotation marks) in the body of your e-mail response and your name will be removed from that mailing list. However, if you opt-out of receiving our announcements and updates about your account, you may no longer have access to areas restricted to account members.

**Correction/Update of Personal Information**

If your personal information changes, you may review/correct/update your personal information previously provided at any time by sending us an email at [support@backpage.com](mailto:support@backpage.com). You may also have your personal profile data deleted from our database by sending us an email to [support@backpage.com](mailto:support@backpage.com). However, if you have your personal profile data deleted from our database, you may forfeit entrance rights to areas restricted to account members and certain benefits for account members.

**Notice of Privacy Rights of California Residents**

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business must either provide this information or permit California residents to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. We qualify for this alternative option. To opt out of having information about you shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes, please contact us at [support@backpage.com](mailto:support@backpage.com).  
****

**Contact Us:**

Email: [Contact us](http://posting.www.backpage.com/classifieds/Contact)   
Telephone: +44 1929290057

International Correspondence:   
Payment Solutions BV.  
Keizersgracht 127  
1015 CJ Amsterdam  
The Netherlands

US Correspondence:  
backpage  
PO Box 192307   
Dallas, TX USA 75219

**Children**

The Site is not intended for children under the age of 13 nor does the Site knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. The Site does not orient this Site toward children or target them as an audience, nor does it screen them from using the Site. Some of the material on this Site is for mature audiences, and parents and guardians should take responsibility for monitoring their children’s use. The Site does not collect or distribute information indicating whether a user is a child.

**Links to Other sites**

This Site provides links and pointers to Web sites maintained by other organizations. The Site provides these links as a convenience to users, but it does not operate, control or endorse such sites. The Site also disclaims any responsibility for the information on those sites and any products or services offered there, and cannot vouch for the privacy policies of such sites. The Site does not make any warranties or representations that any linked sites (or even this Site) will function without error or interruption, that defects will be corrected, or that the sites and their servers are free of viruses and other problems that can harm your computer.

**E-Commerce and Our Secure Server**

We understand that storing data in a secure manner is important.  We store personal information using industry standard, reasonable and technically feasible, physical, technical and administrative safeguards against foreseeable risks, such as unauthorized access.  All commerce transactions that take place on the Site are processed through our secure server in order to make every reasonable effort to insure that your personal information is protected. 

Please be aware that the Site and data storage are run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may, from time to time, require maintenance or experience problems or breaches of security beyond the Site’s control.  We cannot guarantee the security of the information on and sent from the Site. 

On our Site, you may have the opportunity to follow a link to other sites that may be of interest to you.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites or the content provided thereon.  We disclaim any responsibility for transactions conducted on those sites and cannot vouch for the security of the information submitted in those transactions. 

**Policy Changes and Acceptance**

The Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time as we add new features and services, as laws change, and as industry privacy and security best practices evolve.  We display an effective date on the upper left corner of the Privacy Policy so that it will be easier for you to know when there has been a change. Accordingly, you should check the Privacy Policy on a regular basis for the most current privacy practices.  Each time you access, use or browse the Site, you signify your acceptance of the then-current changes to the Privacy Policy applying to your personal information collected by us on and from the effective date of such changes. 

Any changes in the Privacy Policy will take effect upon posting and apply only to information collected from you on and after Last Revised date, unless we provide notice or have other communications with you. 

**More Questions?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, e-mail them to [abuse@backpage.com](mailto:abuse@backpage.com), and be sure to indicate the specific site you’re visiting and the nature of your question or concern.
